So I keep hearing a lot of talk about, you know, black people, we tired, we tired, we tired. That's why we not, we not fighting and we tired. And so my question becomes, so what is the solve for the restoration of resolve? Because the battle is continuing, whether you fight it or not. If you don't fight it at all, it's just going to take all of us.
So what is the actual efforts that are being made? Are you implementing new spiritual practices, either from the ground up or expanding the ones that are already there, right? Are you expanding your mental health practices, whether it's going to therapy or consulting with your doctor about possibly getting on a medication to help you regulate?
Are you expanding beyond Western therapy and going into possibly Reiki, bringing meditation into your practice, et cetera? Are you changing how you eat? Are you putting different things in your body to give you more energy and to not use up all of your energy trying to break down processed foods? Are you changing who's around you?
Are you still around the same people that don't do anything but complain and say that things are bad without actually trying to be a part of changing the things that are bad? Or are you joining in with them, constantly talking about, dang, this is terrible, without doing anything to switch up the process?
Are you expanding your education, perhaps bringing in a certain semblance of fight by having more knowledge about what you're fighting for or what you're fighting against, or even just elevating your anger by knowing that they've been playing us the whole time?
Because let me tell you, the more I learn, the more I want to fight just off the strength of I don't like being played.
And shameless plug, are you bringing art into your life that instills this in you?
Because my show and my book, What Would The Ancestor Say, desires to do that.
Are you bringing exercise into your life?
Because baby, these endorphins, this dopamine, this serotonin, it is within us, but we have to figure out the ways to release it.
Okay?
So everything that people are describing about Black people being tired sounds like depression and or folks literally just giving up.
And that's not an option for me.
So I just listed a bunch of ways in which you can solve to restore resolve.
Because the fight ain't stopping, even if you are.
They want to stand in the way of every move forward.
The only way you can think about your people's struggle is when you are involved in your people's struggle.
We're going to have to change how we relate to each other as human beings.
We're going to fight in solidarity.
Unity.
We're going to have to change how we relate to each other as human beings.